Presenting
S
a
e
n
o
y
a
m
-
z
e
k
i
S
h
i
b
a
k
i
y
a
m
Stable
（小関(おぜき)）アア…　ンンッ…
テイッ！
ウワッ！
（柴木山(しばきやま)）う〜ん…
日に日に 調子落としてるね
His confidence is waning by the day.
All the energy he had on
the first day has evaporated, too.
初日の元気も
すっかり なくなっちまった
Fighting against the pros
is overwhelming him.
（桐仁(きりひと)）
完全に萎縮しちまってますね
プロを相手に
When he feels intimidated, he stiffens up
and isn't able to unleash his full strength.
しかも アウェーだと硬くなって
本来の実力が出ないんスよね
Nationals will be a stern test.
（桐仁）全国は甘くない
I need to come up with a way
to make him feel confident
土俵の中に限らず ふだんから
度胸をつけるための訓練を—
in the ring and in his everyday life.
何か考えないといけないか…
（千比路(ちひろ)）う〜ん…
Captain!
（千比路）部長
（小関）うん？
稽古終わったら
ちょっと俺に つきあえよ
I'm gonna take you somewhere after training.
Okay!
（千比路）よ〜し！
つる子　ちゃんと調べてくれたか？
Tsuruko, did you look into
what I asked you to?
（千鶴子(ちづこ)）千鶴子です
My name is Chizuko.
Hey, Kunisaki...
おい 國崎(くにさき)
堀(ほり)さんまで連れて 一体 どこへ？
Where are we going with Hori-san in tow?
えっ！？　ほ… 堀さん？
H-Hori-san?!
Here's yours, Captain.
ほら 部長も つけろ
You wanna be confident, right?
度胸をつけてえんだろう？
だったら いい方法があるぜ
Well, I know a surefire way.
いや 本当は
１人で行くつもりだったが—
I was gonna go down there by myself,
but if we can build up your confidence
and do scouting at the same time...
部長の度胸試しと偵察とで合わせて
一石二羽(いっせきにわ)作戦だ！
It kills two birds with one rock!
Two birds with one stone, you mean.
（千鶴子）“一石二鳥”です
Scouting?
偵察って ま… まさか…
D-Don't tell me...
Welcome
Kanazawa Kita
High School
Sumo Club
（千比路）おう お前(めえ)ら
Hey, listen up, punks.
We're here to beat the crap outta you!
（千比路）全員 俺らが ぶっ倒す！
（小関）ええっ！？
Presenting
S
a
e
n
o
y
a
m
-
z
e
k
i
S
h
i
b
a
k
i
y
a
m
Stable
（佑真(ゆうま)）
セイッ！　シュッ！
Bout 14
"The Inter High Begins"
セイッ！　セイッ！
Okay, last one!
よし ラスト！
（蛍(けい)）グーッ…
（寺原(てらはら)）
五條(ごじょう)君は 空手の師範からの宿題
Gojo-kun has a regimen set
by his karate instructor,
and Mitsuhashi-kun's
doing strength training.
三ツ橋(みつはし)君は体作りか
They're all training individually
after their group session with us.
（寺原）俺らと
やったあとだってのに 自主練とは
I'm sure they value their
time training with the pros,
（柴木山）彼らにとって
プロと触れ合う時間は貴重だろう
だが それで
満足してもらっちゃ困るよ
but it thankfully isn't
enough to satisfy them.
そのことを知ってか知らずか—
Whether they know it or not,
この２人は
団体決勝での悔しい思いが—
their losses at the team finals have
influenced them in a good way.
いい方向に働いてるようだが…
I wonder what the other two are up to.
さて 残る２人は どうかな
（警官）まあ 彼らも
反省してるようだし 私は これで
Well, looks like they've reflected on
their actions, so I'll be going now.
（千比路）
ハッハッハッ！　まさかな
Unbelievable. I didn't expect
you to actually call the police.
マジで警察に通報するとは
思わなかったぜ
You Odachi jerk!
（米村(よねむら)）おい 大太刀(おおだち) てめえ！
本物のマスクマンが
来たのかと思って ちょっと—
We got scared 'cause we thought some
luchadors had come to wreck up the place!
ドキドキしちゃったじゃねえか
こら！
しかも よく見りゃ—
Furthermore!
That's the mask El Ultimo uses in MMA bouts!
エル･ウルティモの
ＭＭＡ仕様じゃねえか！
Oh, you can tell?
おお 分かる？
Oh, wow, Odachi's got a female manager?
（瀬良(せら)）へえ…
大太刀って 女子マネいるの？
You're a real cutie pie.
And that mask looks great on you!
君 かわいいね
似合ってるよ そのマスク！
Let's swap digits, yeah?
連絡先 教えて！
（相沢(あいざわ)）
やめな 拓海(たくみ)　スマホ割るよ
Cool it, Takumi.
Or your smartphone'll get smashed.
He said we were here to scout,
so why'd we walk in through the front door?
偵察とか言って まさか
正面から敵地に乗り込むなんて…
Devoted Souls are Victorious
Kanazawa Kita High School
Sumo Club
This is Kanazawa Kita High School.
金沢北(かなざわきた)高校
全国優勝経験もあり—
They've triumphed at nationals in the past
and came third in last year's Inter High.
去年のインターハイでも
団体３位
They're a renowned sumo powerhouse!
相撲の名門校だ
Say, Captain Aizawa.
（瀬良）ねえねえ 相沢主将
（相沢）うん？
少しくらい
相手してやってもいいんじゃない？
How about we spar with them a little?
I wanna show this chick my moves, you dig?
俺 この子に
カッコイイところ見せたいな
And after Onimaru beat Tenma,
I feel like we owe them some payback.
それに 鬼丸(おにまる)にやられた典馬(てんま)の
借りも返したいしさ
（相沢）ダメだよ
Absolutely not.
名古屋(なごや)に来たのは 俺たち北高が
強くなるためでしょう？
Kita High's here in Nagoya
to get stronger, remember?
We can't beat Odachi High here
and help make them stronger instead.
ここで 大太刀を負かして—
彼らが強くなる手助けを
しちゃダメだよ
（千比路）なに？
（小関）アア…
What?
Please let Onimaru know that
I'm glad he beat Tenma.
典馬の件は
むしろ 鬼丸に礼を伝えてほしい
敗北は強さへの糧になるからね
おかげで典馬も 今より強くなれる
Losing is a great motivator
for becoming stronger.
So now, Tenma will get stronger.
I won't tell anyone about the intrusion.
この件は これ以上 問題にはしない
I'd prefer to beat you in the ring
than get your school suspended.
出場停止じゃなく
ちゃんと当たって勝ちたいしね
So he says.
…だってさ　どうする？　部長
What do we do, Captain?
Huh? Who, me?
えっ 俺？　えっと…
Um...
Could we fight just one bout?
一番だけでいいんで取りませんか？
軽く 遊びのつもりでもいいんで
Like, some light, playful sparring?
Kanazawa Kita
High School
Sumo Club
Kanazawa Kita
High School
Sumo Club
We're training our hearts out so that
our team comes out on top at nationals.
俺たちはね
本気で全国優勝 目指してるんだ
Kanazawa Kita
High School
Sumo Club
We have no time for "playful" sumo.
遊びで取る相撲なんて
するわけがないだろう
Kanazawa Kita
High School
Sumo Club
There's no comparison between our
rich history, created by past sumo teams,
先輩たちが築いてきた
長い戦いの歴史が…
何もない… 勢いだけで
ここまで来た君たちとは違うんだ
and your nothing team who made it
this far on dumb, beginner's luck alone.
（千鶴子）
黙って帰るなんて意外だった
I didn't expect us to walk out in silence.
Kunisaki-san usually bites back.
國崎さんなら 何か言い返すかと…
So we're a nothing team?
（小関）“何もない”か
（千比路･千鶴子）うん？
ハァ…　ダメだ
やっぱり納得いかないや
Yeah, I really can't take that lying down.
Sorry. You two head on back without me.
悪い　２人は先帰ってて
ハハハッ…
来た甲斐(かい)は あったみてえだ
Looks like it worked.
That guy was dead right.
（千比路）
あいつらの言うことは もっともさ
北高は名門で 俺ら ぽっと出
歴史も浅い
Kita High is prestigious, while we're
basically nobodies with almost zero history.
だが…
But...
The captain isn't going to let anyone
insult the history, however short it is,
“はい そうですか”と
引き下がれるほど—
部長が歩んできたダチ高相撲部の
歴史は軽くねえ
of the sumo club he founded!
Isn't that right, Captain?
そうだろう？　部長
I know how prestigious Kita High is.
（小関）
金沢北高校が名門なのは知ってるよ
でも だからって
俺たちには“何もない”？
But to call us a nothing team...
知らないくせに
They don't know what it's
like to start from nothing!
何もない所から始める苦労も
何も知らないくせに！
They know nothing!
Two lonely years, then
finally finding teammates...
孤独だった２年間
救ってくれた仲間たち
みんなで力を合わせて石(いし)高に勝った
Through working together,
we beat Ishi High.
And he dares to say we're a nothing team?!
それを “何もない”なんて
ひと言で片づけられてたまるか！
We won't be handwaved away like that!
ンンッ…　ハァ…
なに？　忘れ物？
What is it? Forgotten something?
Yeah, I forgot to say something important.
はい
大事なことを伝え忘れてました
Kanazawa Kita High won't be victorious
at nationals this year, either.
金沢北高は
今年も日本一には なれません
Dachi High's sumo club is the strongest!
ダチ高相撲部が最高だってこと
日本一になって証明しますから！
And you'll find that out for yourselves
when we win at nationals!
え… えっと つまり…
U-Uh, I mean...
Don't look down on Dachi High!
ダチ高をナメるなよ！
い… 以上　し… 失礼しました！
Th-That's all!
E-Excuse me!
ま〜た 俺
余計なこと言っちゃったかな
Guess I went and said
something unnecessary again.
The captain's the most determined guy here.
ホントは主将が
いちばん血気盛んなんスよね
I know how badly he wants
to declare that we're gonna win.
言いたくて しかたないんだ
“勝つのは俺らだ”って
Don't worry about that.
We all feel the same way.
問題ねえ
気持ちは全員 お前と同じだ こら！
（相沢）
ああ　優勝するのは俺たちだ
Yeah. We're going to emerge as champions.
ナメてないよ 大太刀高校
We're not looking down on you,
Odachi High School.
We've studied Onimaru and the momentum
that took you past Ishi High.
鬼丸も
石高も倒した その勢いも—
研究させてもらってますよ
本気でね
Very carefully, at that!
Steel yourself for it already!
（小関）いいかげん腹を決めろ
今日まで何度 誓ってきた？
I've told myself that so many times!
I'm going to make Dachi High
national champions!
俺が ダチ高を日本一にするんだ！
Yes! Now, keep pushing!
そう！　そこで休むな！
（柴木山）よ〜し いいぞ
今の感覚 忘れるなよ
Okay, good.
Don't forget that flow.
Thank you very much!
（蛍）ありがとうございました
Jeez, do you even know how lucky you are?
まったく…　分かってんのか？
Getting to actually spar with
Master Shibakiyama is a big deal.
すごいことなんだぜ
柴木山親方の胸を借りるなんて
正直 お前が羨ましいよ
To be honest, I'm a little envious.
僕も たまには体を動かさないとね
Well, I need to get my exercise, too.
まだまだ高校生の相手ぐらいなら
務まるよ
I can still hold my own against
high-school students at least.
Master, you really are incredible!
確かに 親方は すごいです
Your instructions are more precise and
easier to understand than our instructor's.
監督なんかより
教え方も丁寧で分かりやすいし
His explanations are crude,
and he's often inflexible.
（蛍）
この人 説明が雑だし 余裕ないし
指導者としては まだまだですね
He's still got a lot to learn, hasn't he?
Hey...
お前 親方と比べるのは ナシだろう
Don't go comparing me to the master.
ハハハハッ…　年季が違うさ
まだ高１だろう？　よくやってるよ
It comes with age.
You're still a first-year, aren't you?
You're on the right track!
Man, I know I've got a lot to learn still.
くそ…　分かってんだよ
俺が まだまだ未熟だってのは
俺だって頑張ってんだよ
ちくしょう！
I'm trying my best here, dammit.
ハハハハッ…
なにヘコんでんですか？
Don't beat yourself up.
Sure, there are things you can improve,
確かに
少し頼りないところもありますけど
そもそも ダチ高と柴木山部屋を
つなげたのも監督だし
but you're the one who put Dachi High
in touch with the Shibakiyama Stable.
And you can see for yourself how
much better I've gotten since joining!
それに ほら
僕も入ったころに比べ—
なかなか いい感じになってきたと
思いません？
まあな　お前は よくやってるよ
True. You're working hard.
It's not just me.
僕だけじゃない
監督には感謝してるんです
We're all grateful to you, Instructor.
Thank you very much.
（蛍）ありがとうございます
（桐仁）えっ？
I'm expressing gratitude
on behalf of the team.
（蛍）
みんなを代表して お礼を言います
H-Hey, wh-what are you saying?
あっ な… 何言ってんだ 急に！
Idiot. Save that gesture for
when we stand victorious.
バカ！
そういうのは優勝するまで取っとけ
まだ戦いは終わってねえんだ
…たく
We've got plenty more fights
ahead of us. Sheesh.
Excuse me, Master.
（蛍）あの…　親方
（柴木山）うん？
（蛍）もう少しだけ
つきあってもらってもいいですか？
Can we keep training for a little longer?
I'd like you to spar with him, too.
この人とも
稽古をつけてやってください
はぁ？　な… 何を言ってる？
Wh-What do you mean?
（桐仁）あ〜 ハハッ…
おいおい よしてくれ
Hey, now...
Don't go there.
Is this because I said I was envious?
さっき
羨ましいなんて言ったからか？
You know about my condition.
俺の事情は知ってるだろう
I can't fight for more than 20 seconds.
俺は 20秒以上 戦えない欠陥力士だ
I'm a defective sumo wrestler.
Of course I know all that.
もちろん知ってますよ
でも 20秒なら戦えるんでしょう？
But that's 20 whole seconds
you can use to fight.
（蛍）
ずっと気になってたんですよね
It's been bugging me for a while...
インターハイ予選の団体戦—
Why didn't you put yourself down
as a reserve for the Inter High?
補欠としての
選手登録すらしてなかったこと
Ushio Hinomaru
Mitsuhashi
Reserve
Even in our dojo, you haven't done any
sumo since you fought Hinomaru-san.
稽古場でも火ノ丸(ひのまる)さんと戦って以来
相撲は一度も取ってない
（蛍）なんでですか？
（桐仁）ンンッ…
Why is that?
That's what I'm willing to
sacrifice to be an instructor.
それが俺の 監督としての覚悟
Not listing myself as a team member
shows how determined I am.
選手登録しないのは
その決意表明だ
I swore I'd focus on being an
instructor so you guys can win.
監督として
みんなを勝たせると誓ったんだ
But you must still miss fighting.
でも 未練が
全くないわけじゃないんでしょう？
（蛍）部長と火ノ丸さんとの
戦いに向ける熱いまなざしは…
That intense look in your eye when you
watched the captain and Hinomaru-san fight...
（握りしめる音）
あの握り拳は—
That clenched fist...
Was that really just how
you felt as an instructor?
本当に 監督としての
ものだけだったんですか？
何だ？　何なんだ？
どうして俺を土俵に上げたがる？
What is this? What's this about?
Why are you trying to drag me into the ring?
まさか
今更になって おじけづいて—
You aren't chickening out and
asking me to take your place, are you?
代わりに
出てくれってんじゃねえだろうな？
俺の本心は知ってるだろう？
土俵への未練も否定はしない
You know how I feel!
I don't deny that I miss the sumo ring.
でも それは
みんなには関係のないことだ
But that's got nothing
to do with the team!
Nothing to do with us?
関係ない？　関係ないって何だよ？
How can you say that?
Before we're instructor and pupils,
僕らは
監督と選手である以前に—
we're all high-schoolers who love sumo!
相撲好きの
ひとりの高校生じゃないか！
I want to respect your decision
to be an instructor.
監督としての覚悟も尊重はしたい
けど やっぱり おかしいだろう！
But it's just not right!
どうして君ひとりが
犠牲にならなきゃいけない？
Why do you have to sacrifice so much for us?
ひとりで抱え込むなよ！
Don't carry it all on your shoulders!
We're not so unreliable that we need
you to suppress yourself for us, Kirihito!
僕らを生かすために
自分を殺さなきゃならないほど—
僕らは
もう頼りなくはないだろう 桐仁！
I'm not saying this out of pity.
（蛍）別に同情して
こんな話をしてるんじゃない
Hinomaru-san got injured, right?
火ノ丸さんがケガをしたでしょう
また負傷者が出ないとは限らない
The same could happen to any one of us.
It'd be a weight off all our minds if we had
a sixth team member we could rely on.
そんなときに 頼れる６人目の
控え選手がいたら—
どんなに心強いだろうってね
もちろん
レギュラーの座を譲る気はない
Of course, I don't want to give up
my place on the team sheet.
I'll compete with you for it and make it mine.
君と競争して 勝ち取ってみせる
So let's all practice sumo together!
だから これからは みんなと一緒に
相撲の稽古をしよう！
お… 俺は…
I...
（柴木山）よし　辻(つじ)君 おいで
Okay, get out here, Tsuji-kun.
いや 俺は その…
ま… 廻(まわ)しも着けてないし
Oh, no, I didn't mean...
I-I don't have a mawashi belt on...
Never mind. Come as you are.
（柴木山）いいよ そのまま
I don't let just anyone spar with me.
この僕が胸を貸すなんて
そうあることじゃないぞ
Dammit all...
くそ…　こんなの…
There's no way I could
refuse an offer like that!
我慢できるわけ
ねえじゃねえか！
Spirit!
（蛍）はっきよい！
（桐仁）ンンッ！
グッ…　これが
50になろうかって人の当たりかよ
How can a nearly 50-year-old man
headbutt so hard?!
Damn, I'm so nervous,
my breathing is erratic.
ヤバイ　緊張で息が乱れる
I won't even last 20 seconds like this!
これじゃ 20秒も もたねえぞ！
You know I'm like this...
こんな俺でも
お前らは やっていいって—
And you guys are still saying I can fight?
そう言うんだな？
みんな…
Guys...
Thanks!
ありがとうよ！
Tokugetsu
Oxygen
Here!
（蛍）これを！
（桐仁）ハァ…
Tokugetsu
Oxygen
お… 親方　大丈夫ですか？
M-Master... are you okay?
（柴木山）フフフッ…　こりゃ
冴ノ山(さえのやま)でも連れてこなきゃ足りんな
I'll need to get Saenoyama to take you on.
まだ高１だろう
You're still a first-year.
If you aren't sure what you want,
try something different.
迷っているのなら
いろいろ やってみるといい
But have you really not
been doing any training?
しかし
本当に何もしてなかったのか？
全然 やれるじゃないか
You're in really good shape.
No, I did just enough to
maintain my muscle mass.
（桐仁）いや
まあ 筋力を維持する程度には…
I see.
なるほどな　みんなが
必死になるのも うなずける
I now understand why
they're all so determined.
Yes, he's strong!
ええ　強いんですよ この人！
Stop that.
よせよ
Our best formation...
ベストな形 …か
I don't know how much use I'll be to the team,
どこまで役に立てるか
分からないが—
but even as trainer, I'll do everything I can
to help us to victory at nationals!
監督の俺も全部 使って
みんなを日本一にしてみせる！
Presenting
S
a
e
n
o
y
a
m
-
z
e
k
i
S
h
i
b
a
k
i
y
a
m
Stable
That week sure went fast.
（柴木山）
あっという間の１週間だったな
Are you really going back already?
（寺原）
本当に もう帰っちまうのか？
名古屋場所も見ていけばいいのに
You could hang around and watch
the Nagoya tournament.
In order to put your lessons to good use,
皆さんの協力に応えるためにも
僕らは稽古を続けなきゃいけません
we need to continue our training.
うむ…　プロはプロの
君たちは君たちの戦場を戦い抜こう
We pros will fight our battles,
and you will fight your own.
Yes, sir!
（一同）はい！
（佑真）おう
俺は このまま空手道場に行くけど
I'm heading straight over to the karate dojo.
We'll go to the school to train.
俺らは学校で稽古ッスね
火ノ丸の仕上がりも見たいし
I want to see what Hinomaru's learned.
Before that, Kirihito...
（火ノ丸）その前に 桐仁
（桐仁）うん？
I want to see the video
of Tottori Hakuro again.
鳥取白楼(とっとりはくろう)のビデオ
もう一度 見たい
I want to sear the image of Tennoji-san,
the opponent I must defeat, into my brain.
（火ノ丸）改めて 天王寺(てんのうじ)さんの…
倒すべき敵の姿を
この目に焼き付けたい
I won't look away. I'll face him head-on.
今度こそ
顔を背けずに真っ正面から
フフッ…　分かった
You got it.
Come to think of it, where are
the captain and Kunisaki-san?
そういえば 部長と國崎さんは？
２人とも先に降りていきましたけど
They both got off the train already.
They probably had stuff
they wanted to work on.
何か考えがあるんだろう
それでいい　それぞれが
自分に足りないものを自覚して—
Which is fine.
Each of us must figure out
what we're lacking,
強くなるために
ベストを尽くすだけだ
and do our very best to grow stronger.
（しこを踏む音）
（女性）なに？　あれ　相撲？
What is he doing? Sumo?
（女性）フッ…　なに？　あれ
（女性）何かの罰ゲーム？
What's wrong with him?
Did he lose a bet or something?
Mom, what's that guy doing?
（男の子）
ママ　あの人 何してるの？
Don't look at him!
（母親）見ちゃいけません！
ウウ…　恥ずかしくて死にそうだ
I'm gonna die of embarrassment.
でも これを平常心で
できるようになれば きっと…
But if I can stay calm
while doing this, then...
If confidence is what I lack,
I just need to find some.
度胸がないなら つければいい
俺が俺を変えるんだ！
I'm going to change myself!
Sakamoto
Bone-setting
Clinic
（沙田(さだ)）もしもし 主将？
Hello, Captain?
ええ
もう だいぶ よくなってきましたよ
Yeah, it's feeling much better.
There was nothing wrong with the bone.
（沙田）骨に異常は なかったし
これなら個人戦も出ればよかったわ
I wish I'd taken part in
the individual contest now.
ハハハハッ…
冗談ですよ　怒らないで
I'm joking! Don't fly off the handle.
I'll be back in training tomorrow.
あしたから 俺も本格的に
稽古戻りますんで　じゃあね
Later!
How about starting now instead of tomorrow?
（千比路）あしたからと言わず
今から どうだい？　三日月宗近(みかづきむねちか)
Mikazuki Munechika.
This is the very best thing I can think of.
（千比路）
これが 俺の考えるベストだ
Please. Help me train.
頼む　俺の稽古に つきあってくれ
Ishigami
High
School
Sumo
Club
Jeez.
（金盛(かなもり)）…たく
俺は もう主将じゃねえっつうの
I'm not captain anymore.
（間宮(まみや)）お〜し 再開すっぞ
（部員たち）はい！
Okay, back to training.
Yes, sir!
Yo, Captain Mamiya!
（真田(さなだ)）よっ！　間宮主将
Oh, Sanada-san!
ゲッ…　真田さん
何しに来たんスか？
What are you doing here?
（真田）テレビつけてみ
面白いもん やってるぜ
Turn on the TV.
There's something interesting on.
If you want to sear Tennoji into
your brain, this should help.
（桐仁）天王寺の姿を
焼き付けたいんだったら—
ちょうどいい
（火ノ丸）うん？
（リポーター）高校相撲が—
The hype surrounding high school
sumo is reaching fever pitch.
かつてないほどの
盛り上がりを見せています
Today, we're visiting the
powerhouse that is favorite
（リポーター）今回は そんな中
来月 行われるインターハイで—
Tottori Hakuro
Sumo Club
to win a record seventh straight
Inter High championship next month.
前人未到の
７連覇への期待がかかる強豪校—
This is Tottori Hakuro High School.
鳥取白楼高校に
おジャマしています
The Tottori Hakuro sumo club
is renowned as a place where...
鳥取白楼相撲部は
日本全国のみならず—
モンゴルからの留学生を—
Mongolian exchange students train
side-by-side with Japanese wrestlers.
積極的に受け入れていることでも
知られています
They've produced many
pro sumo wrestlers,
巣立っていった力士も大勢いますが
中でも有名なのは やはり—
but of course, the best known is...
the current strongest yokozuna, Jino-zeki.
現役最強の横綱 刃皇関(じんおうぜき)でしょう
先週 母校を訪れた刃皇関は—
He visited his old school and trained
with the current team members.
後輩たちと共に
たっぷり汗を流しました
（礼奈(れいな)）えっ！？
おチビは数秒だけだったのに
He only spent a few seconds with shorty.
そんな横綱 刃皇関も
熱視線を送る高校生力士が—
Yokozuna Jino-zeki's
attention was focused squarely
on the strongest high
school sumo wrestler:
高校相撲界 最強の男—
National treasure Dojikiri Yasutsuna,
AKA Tennoji Shido-kun.
国宝 童子切安綱(どうじきりやすつな) 天王寺獅童(しどう)君です
（天王寺）
どうも　主将の天王寺です
Hello, I'm the team's captain, Tennoji.
My, you are big, aren't you?
（リポーター）大きいですね
ホントに高校生ですか？
Are you really a high school student?
Oh, no, there will be plenty
of people my size at nationals.
（天王寺）いやいや　僕くらいのは
全国行けば ゴロゴロいますよ
I'm the favorite to win
my third individual title,
個人３連覇も期待されてますけど
簡単やありません
but it won't be easy.
Everyone there will be a rival.
（天王寺）全員がライバルです
（狩谷(かりや)）フン…
Talk about giving boring answers...
つまんねえ受け答えばっか
しやがって…
You're so modest.
（リポーター）謙虚ですね
しかし 高校入学以来 公式戦は無敗
But you've won every official match
you've contested since entering high school.
Tell us, what's your secret?
その強さの秘訣(ひけつ)について
お聞きしたいのですが
My secret?
（天王寺）秘訣ですか？
I don't do anything special.
別に特別なことなんて
何もないですね
I'm not the son of a yokozuna,
（天王寺）
僕は横綱の息子でもなければ—
or the younger brother of an ozeki.
大関の弟でもない
If I had to pin down why, maybe it's because
I love sumo more than anyone else.
ただ強いて言うなら 俺が誰より
相撲が好きってことやと思います
I love sumo the most,
and I train the hardest.
俺が いちばん相撲が好きで
俺が いちばん相撲の稽古をしてる
That's why I'm the strongest.
だから俺が いちばん強い
He's openly challenging the other
high school sumo wrestlers.
（駿海(しゅんかい)）
高校生力士に向けた宣戦布告だな
His humility is authentic,
（駿海）
謙虚さも決してウソではない
but under that dignified facade
だが その品位という皮を
ひと皮むけば “鬼”
is a demon.
なるほど
I see.
He's shackled by being a high-school athlete,
高校という冠がついちゃいるが
その風格は紛れもなく横綱だ
but he has the unmistakable
attitude of a yokozuna.
Just our luck.
（桐仁）ツイてねえよな
Why did we have to compete in this era?
なんだって
こんな世代に当たっちまったのか
No, you've got it all wrong.
いや そうじゃねえだろう
It's Tennoji's continued position
at the top of the pile
天王寺が
最強であり続けたからこそ—
that has made those chasing him so strong.
その背中を追う者たちも
強くなることができた
Without him, I wouldn't be where I am.
あの人がいなかったら ワシも
きっと ここまで来れちゃいない
So I'm grateful to him.
感謝すらしてる
Now, I'll take his head and become
the strongest high school sumo wrestler!
あとは その首いただいて
ワシが高校最強になるだけじゃ
Just you wait, nationals.
（火ノ丸）待ってろよ 全国
ワシの全てを ぶつけてやる！
I'm coming for you with all I've got.
フゥ…
Are you watching me?
見とるか？
この体でも ここまで来れたぞ
I've come so far with this body.
Ushio
Family
Grave
I'll win the Inter High.
インターハイ 勝ってくるぜ！
（男性）ウオ〜ッ！
いけいけ！　やれ〜！
Go! Go!
National
High
School
Sports
Tournament
National
High
School
Sumo
Championship
Do it!
Yes, good work!
（男性）よ〜し いいぞ！
（男性）まず１勝！
That's one win!
It's good to be back.
懐かしいな
小学生横綱のとき以来か
I haven't been here since becoming
the elementary school yokozuna.
We're finally here.
とうとう来たな
We get to do sumo here.
ここで相撲が取れるなんて…
Awesome. I'm all fired up!
いいね　血が たぎるぜ！
（蛍）アア…
（桐仁）なにビビってんだ？
Don't let yourself get intimidated.
今まで練習で やってきたことを
ぶつけるだけだろう
All you have to do is
fight like we practiced.
You're right.
そうですね　ンッ…
Okay! Let's show them how
strong Dachi High's sumo club is!
さあ 俺たち ダチ高相撲部の強さ
見せつけてやろうぜ！
Yeah!
ウッ…　みんな 見てる
でも これも度胸をつけるためだ！
Everyone's looking at me.
But I'm doing this to
build up my confidence!
Hey, you there.
（警官）ちょっと 君
（小関）えっ？
What do you think you're doing?
（警官）ここで何してる？
（小関）いや ただの相撲の稽古で
怪しい者では…
Oh, just some sumo training.
Nothing suspicious!
Next Bout  "Onimaru Kunitsuna and Dojikiri Yasutsuna"
This will definitely make
me more confident.
これは度胸つくわぁ…